Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Hey, Brian, how's it going?
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Oh, Jessie, how's it going?
Jessie Zhang: Great.
Brian Malone: out there.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Huh.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Trickling in, finally we outnumber the bots.
Jessie Zhang: -
Brian Malone: Supposedly.
Brian Malone: We're gonna still not confirm that you are actually not a bot.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I… honestly don't know how I can prove it.
Brian Malone: I know, you've been struggling with this. It's like your existential angst.
Jessie Zhang: You can approve it, but I just dare not to say it, because it's not politically correct things.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I mean, bots can bleep.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: You're coming to, you're coming to, MCPCon in, san Jose?
Jessie Zhang: Who am I asking?
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: You, Jessie.
Jessie Zhang: No.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Oh.
Jessie Zhang: What was that?
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: There's the MCP DevCon?
Sanjeev Suresh: I'll do that.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Jim.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Excellent. So… When can I meet you face-to-face to get this non-politically correct answer?
Jessie Zhang: I'm going to the AI, conference in Pier 48.
Jessie Zhang: In October.
Jessie Zhang: Anyone's gonna go there?
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: You're 48.
Jessie Zhang: kind of fun. I attended last one.
Sanjeev Suresh: What's it called?
Jessie Zhang: Okay.
Jessie Zhang: Somebody had conference.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Somebody else… I'm gonna look it up.
Jessie Zhang: Yeah, I'll have to look at it.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: The user is looking for a semi-I conference. What should I Oh, no.
Jessie Zhang: Let me see it.
Jessie Zhang: I just purchased tickets a few days ago.
Sanjeev Suresh: You should, I mean, like, if possible, you should try to come for the MCPCon one, so I think that's organized by the Agenticia Foundation. It's, like, I think October 22nd.
Jessie Zhang: What's that?
Sanjeev Suresh: On October 22nd in San Jose.
Jessie Zhang: Okay, okay.
Sanjeev Suresh: like.
Jessie Zhang: And…
Sanjeev Suresh: Do it.
Jessie Zhang: Guess what? This one is called the AI Conference.
Jessie Zhang: I didn't say it wrong. It is called at the AI conference. Yeah, I'll try, figure out that one.
Jessie Zhang: And so Sanjeev and I were talking, so I am switching out my OpenAI and, Anthropic contact for the speaker.
Sanjeev Suresh: And did you hear back?
Jessie Zhang: It just depends on when. We gotta have to say when and what.
Jessie Zhang: Okay.
Sanjeev Suresh: Hey, Jordan, welcome back. How was your vacation?
Jordan Augé: Thank you, very good.
Jordan Augé: Return is a bit tough, but…
Jordan Augé: How are you, everyone?
Jessie Zhang: kid.
Sanjeev Suresh: Dang good.
Jordan Augé: Okay, so…
Jordan Augé: I guess, we can start, so… so, as usual, I guess the, the, the agenda will be, quick sharing,
Jordan Augé: about different things, then we can review the state of the gap deliverable, mostly the survey part, because this is how we want to solve the…
Jordan Augé: positioning, etc.
Jordan Augé: And finally, we can do a few updates about, taxonomy, D1, etc.
Jordan Augé: So…
Jordan Augé: about sharing, so I know you were talking about conferences before I joined, so I wanted to ask you, who was going to AgentCon, MCPCon, because there is an instance in Amsterdam in September, so I will be going with a few colleagues, and then you have the San Jose one.
Jordan Augé: Some colleagues of mine are going, but I won't be, so I'll…
Sanjeev Suresh: Like, I'll be going to the San Jose one.
Jordan Augé: Okay.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: It really looks like I'm going to San Jose, and my colleague Miria
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: is going to the Amsterdam one, so whoever's going to Amsterdam actually gets the better half of Ericsson.
Jessie Zhang: I'm gonna try to go to San Jose one, I didn't know, so I kind of signed up for another one.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Excellent, I'll get the story back.
Jessie Zhang: Yeah, yeah, so we can meet. That'd be great.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I'm gonna ask the Discord people to put two…
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Two channels for the conferences, so that we can, like, Know who's going where.
Jordan Augé: It'll be nice to know who in the working group is going, so maybe I will ping the channel also to…
Jordan Augé: To see who is participating, it could be the occasion to meet and curse also.
Sanjeev Suresh: And Jessie, maybe, like, if you are doing, like, an event, it can also be somewhere, like, around that as a, like, a side event of that, of, yeah, potentially. We can talk about it later in that meeting.
Jessie Zhang: Yeah, we can also bring it up at the end of this meeting, so…
Sanjeev Suresh: Yep.
Jessie Zhang: we're gonna get more qualified survey participants, right? So there are a few things that Sanjeevan and I were chatting. Yeah, I think this conference is a good place, since it's the AI… the Linux Foundation, right?
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah.
Sanjeev Suresh: I'll have to drop off at 9.40 today, because I have another meeting at 9.45, so I just…
Jordan Augé: So anyway, for the intro, I guess, do you have anything to… you're willing to share? Otherwise, I think…
Jordan Augé: We can jump to… The Soviet?
Jordan Augé: Yep, so… Maybe, Sanjeev, all yours for the D2 survey part?
Jordan Augé: I did not follow the previous meeting, so I don't know where you stopped. Casper updated me, but…
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, let me just quickly share my screen.
Sanjeev Suresh: So we have a survey version that is out in this pier.
Sanjeev Suresh: like, I do want everyone, like, maybe even we can take some time, 10 minutes in this meeting, to actually do the survey, so there's a Google Forms option.
Sanjeev Suresh: In which you can go and, like, actually do the survey. The main feedback is just on, like, I mean, like, how difficult is it to do?
Sanjeev Suresh: Are we getting the right signals? Like, already I feel the complexity is on the higher side, like, 10 minutes of, like, focused doing the survey, and this is a free survey.
Sanjeev Suresh: yeah, so…
Sanjeev Suresh: Like, maybe… I mean, something useful for us to do, like, like, actually in the meeting might also be actually, like, doing a survey here.
Sanjeev Suresh: And getting, like, live feedback.
Sanjeev Suresh: I don't know if you want to do that. Jordan, thoughts?
Jordan Augé: Yep, I think it's a good idea.
Jessie Zhang: So, Sanjeev, I had one comment, but I couldn't add it. The AI maturity, right? The size alone, probably not good, but we can deduct from other questions.
Jessie Zhang: Somehow I couldn't log in again, so…
Jessie Zhang: Because then maybe I had that comment, so I was struggling. Do you have the link of that Google…
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, let me share this… In the chat…
Jordan Augé: And if I understood well, so the idea would be to have this week to continue getting reviews, and then by the end of the week, stop the review so that we can merge the PR and have, at least the first one running right.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, some… so I think we still need to get, maybe Casper can add, once he's back. So this is just… we have reviewed it internally, like Jessie and I met also separately since the last meeting.
Sanjeev Suresh: Like, I'm not sure of the process of getting it reviewed across working groups.
Sanjeev Suresh: Or at the leads level, because, I mean, this is like a survey we are sending out, right? So that might be something that still needs to happen. So this is just… the end of this week is the review within our working group. Matthew.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I just wanted to share for that, the Security Working Group has this,
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: This, working group called the checklist.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: It's a terrible name.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: But basically, it's to make sure that people don't, reinvent the wheel.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: It's being, pushed by Govind.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: And he… I think he would be your best ally for getting this to everyone fast.
Sanjeev Suresh: Security…
Sanjeev Suresh: Go in.
Jordan Augé: So next Monday, we have a working group chair meeting also, so if we have something ready, that's also the opportunity to share with all the chairs that are joining, so that they can relay also.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: So, Jordan, I have to warn you about Monday.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Now, as a European, you're incredibly industrious, but North America is closed. We have a… we have a red day.
Jessie Zhang: Have a day.
Jordan Augé: True.
Jordan Augé: That might delay. I don't know if they will delay the chair's meeting, or put the next…
Jordan Augé: Maybe it will be offline meeting, but I can still,
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Yeah. No, it's good to bring it up, I'm just warning… I'm trying to temper your expectations.
Jordan Augé: It's a good point.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: People are making fun of… making fun of the fact that North America never does work well, or Europe is working really hard.
Jordan Augé: Yeah, we had a full month off in France.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, and I think something else we need to also, like, like, I see, like, actually do the survey right now, something we need to talk about is how do we get, like, what is the target participation we are shooting for, and how do we get that, right?
Sanjeev Suresh: And a way of… I mean, we can, of course, like, maybe send it out as part of some sort of newsletter of the Agentic Foundation.
Sanjeev Suresh: But how many people would actually read and fill that out? No, I would not imagine very many if it's, like, a really, I mean, heavy survey.
Sanjeev Suresh: So, what other forums, like, possibly could we publicize it in some events? Can we run some sort of, like, accuracy and reliability-specific event, either in person or virtual?
Sanjeev Suresh: And publicize it there, so those are, like, some avenues we are talking about, and Jessie… So I am in touch with the Bay Area organizers of the Agentic AI Foundation, and I help with, like, running two MCP-related meetups over the last two months.
Sanjeev Suresh: So I know, like, I mean, like, if you want to run a smaller-scale meetup, I know who to talk to here, to find venues and whatnot, and Jessie was looking at if she can find, potentially, like, some, like, speakers, either from, like, she mentioned she had some, friends from OpenAI.
Sanjeev Suresh: That may potentially be speakers also. So, those are, like, some of the things that are happening.
Jordan Augé: Yesterday, we submitted the report for July to technical committee, and part of the questions I asked if the TC is able also to help us with the dissemination of the survey. And our main contact for the working group is David Suryapara.
Jordan Augé: So, maybe we'll have some feedback within a few days or so, by the end of the week, I hope to see what they say.
Jordan Augé: I'll share on Discord.
Sanjeev Suresh: Okay.
Sanjeev Suresh: Sorry to guard, Jessie.
Jessie Zhang: Go ahead, go ahead, go ahead. Finish it.
Sanjeev Suresh: No, I think that's a major risk right now I'm seeing of, like, actual survey participation, and getting to… and, like, what are we shooting for? Is it, like, 500?
Jessie Zhang: I kind of felt like I probably need to be…
Sanjeev Suresh: Larger.
Jessie Zhang: than that, because you're gonna, you're gonna get some results, like, we're chatting, right?
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah.
Jessie Zhang: They just…
Jessie Zhang: very quickly, and so they're not reading it. Then we have to get rid of those answers, because those are not going to be accurate.
Jessie Zhang: So you have to think of a percentage of participants. Their answers are not going to be useful.
Sanjeev Suresh: So maybe, like, I don't know, 1,000 to… like, do you have, like, any sense on what we should target for, Jessie?
Jessie Zhang: I would imagine, like, a thousand-something, so let's say maybe there's 10, 20 person in the search.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah.
Jessie Zhang: Okay.
Sanjeev Suresh: I think that's a…
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: We're very lucky.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: That we are a bunch of data nerds here.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: It's very easy to find who is faking it through standard deviation when you have a 20-question survey like this.
Jessie Zhang: Yep.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Basic data science will eliminate the fake ones fast. Speaking of which, can you eliminate all my test runs in the survey?
Sanjeev Suresh: Yes, I mean, think of it as, like, I'll put up a new form for the actual service, think of this as prototype.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I'll keep… so I can keep testing and filling it with garbage.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yep.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Perfect, I'll keep testing then.
Jessie Zhang: I think we have to, like, probably run, either Cloud or something to go through some of the questions, because I… even though I read it one… one at a time, I get feedback, when I read it, I still have to look in for the answer, because
Jessie Zhang: either the, like, this involvement and leads to most, or most to list, right? This I have to actually find in the middle of somewhere, saying, oh, yeah, we do a lot.
Jessie Zhang: So maybe we can… we have to reorganize the answers a little bit, maybe reward a little bit.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, and Jessie, I'll share, like, I mean, once this PR is done also, like, or, like, I mean, immediately after this itself, like, I'll share the… I mean, some sort of, like, form link, in which we can build the final version, and we can make, I mean, minor manual edits as well.
Jessie Zhang: But this is good, we all take it, right, and give more feedback, because I thought I would know very, very well now, but I still… actually, the first question has to go look for the answers.
Jessie Zhang: Amanda.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, and this first question is the only exit one, so if you say that's only… you only have second-hand knowledge, or you have only done a demo, it exits fast.
Jessie Zhang: Yeah, because I found that middle one,
Jessie Zhang: Because we did a lot already.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah.
Jessie Zhang: Yeah, it's good. I figured this will… we can get more feedback from people.
Nicolas Bonnet: How can we provide feedback on,
Nicolas Bonnet: I'm in the middle of the survey, and I want to provide structured feedback. What would be the best way to do this?
Jessie Zhang: there's a PR. I did this, I'm writing it down right now. I say question one, then I say, here, then you can go to the PR. Maybe you can clean up, maybe we can…
Jessie Zhang: Sanjeev, we can just merge the PR so they can… Did you…
Nicolas Bonnet: Do you want us to do this on a per-question basis, or you want it in the PR, or do you want it…
Sanjeev Suresh: I shouldn't take me…
Jessie Zhang: Both, right?
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, yeah. Yeah, I mean, if you have something, like, live you want to ask right now, go ahead, like, if you want to provide more structured feedback, PR is probably better. And yeah, either as a
Sanjeev Suresh: together thing or a typical question level. Like, especially if you are proposing a new question, like, I would suggest, like, if you can actually give the question with the options.
Sanjeev Suresh: And also, even potentially some other question you would replace in its place, that you think… that you think is more important.
Nicolas Bonnet: I have maybe two quick feedback. One is more as a designer of survey.
Nicolas Bonnet: Rather than as an… to answer. It's like, very often when I…
Nicolas Bonnet: I design a survey, I think about, what am I going to do with the answer?
Nicolas Bonnet: And I wonder whether it's worth to ask ourselves, what are we going to do with the answers? To make sure that, for example.
Nicolas Bonnet: The distance between the answers are separate enough that
Nicolas Bonnet: you can… we can do something with the answer. So I feel like sometimes some of the answers are so close to each other that I would not be sure what to do with the answer, so I wonder whether it's worth to look at it again and say, assume we have all those answers, what are we going to do with it? And the other…
Nicolas Bonnet: My first feeling is that it feels… That it's not necessarily… Quite specific to…
Nicolas Bonnet: Accuracy and Reliability, and maybe it's… maybe it's okay. I'm in the middle, I didn't finish, so I should wait, but I feel like if it needs to be tied to Accuracy… is it properly tied to.
Sanjeev Suresh: So from question… so from question 9 onwards, it's, like, specific to Accuracy and Reliability.
Nicolas Bonnet: Okay, perfect.
Sanjeev Suresh: And I think first, maybe 4 or 5 questions is just general, like, con… like, who are you? And then next 3 or 4 is just, what are your biggest problems? Of which accuracy and reliability are two?
Sanjeev Suresh: Like, where does Accuracy and Reliability fit in with all the other things that you care about? And then from question 9 onwards, it's Accuracy and Reliability.
Nicolas Bonnet: It might make sense, and it's a little trick, it's not much, but in the wording of the question.
Nicolas Bonnet: to reiterate the language of accuracy and reliability, so that it sort of anchors this to the scope of what we're doing. It's a small thing, because it… sometimes I feel like they're… as I was processing, I felt like they were disconnected. It's just a small, stylish… stylistic,
Nicolas Bonnet: recommendation. But it, it's, it's, it's good.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, and if you're in that…
Jessie Zhang: Yeah.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, and if you have any specific, like, words or, like, terms from our working group that, that you would propose replacing something else, please leave us feedback.
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah, yeah, I'll do that directly in the PR.
Jessie Zhang: It's a good feedback. We're also looking at seeing how we can use the data. The survey is not just for the survey, right? It's afterwards how we can use the data, so that we have to go through a little bit more.
Jessie Zhang: Once we get some sample data, Sanjeev, we can run some, like, analysis, see how we can use it, and what's missing, then we can actually also do more.
Sanjeev Suresh: Matthew.
Sanjeev Suresh: You're on mute.
Jessie Zhang: It's the headset problem.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: How is it now?
Sanjeev Suresh: Yes.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I was wondering if we could open… so, for Nicolas work, it sounds like a GitHub issue.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Might be a better fit.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: For stream-of-consciousness stuff, rather than,
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Rather than comments on the PR, because there, you'd have to inject, and maybe it's going to be affecting 4 or 5 things, and be all over the place.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Would, issues, be,
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: it's kind of weird to put issues on a PR,
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: But what would you think of that as an approach?
Sanjeev Suresh: I would actually pro- like, I would actually prefer just the PR itself, just so that it stays, like, everything in the same place, or maybe on Discord, if you want to just chat some before you put some comments. Like, like, yeah, I'm active on Discord, too.
Nicolas Bonnet: Okay, I'll do whatever is…
Nicolas Bonnet: works best for you guys, but I think Matthew picked up on my way of thinking. I'm a stream-of-conscious kind of person, so sometimes it was… when I was looking at the PR last time…
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: brother.
Nicolas Bonnet: It was hard for me to sort of,
Nicolas Bonnet: break it down, so… so… but I'll figure… I'll do whatever works for you from a technical viewpoint, but it was a little bit of a challenge for me, to be honest, yeah.
Sanjeev Suresh: I mean, feel free to just message on Discord to, like, I mean, we can just chat there, AIC.
Nicolas Bonnet: I can do that, too.
Nicolas Bonnet: Okay, cool.
Jessie Zhang: PR action, you kind of feel like you drag… you are focused on one problem, sometimes it's lost the whole thing, right? Because digging into one. So what I'm doing right now, I'm just on the side, I say, question one, here's my feedback. Question two, then I'm gonna probably…
Jessie Zhang: Don't fit back.
Nicolas Bonnet: Okay, cool. I'll do multiple iterations, and I'll go through one time, just to get the overall feel.
Nicolas Bonnet: Take notes, and then I'll do question by question. I'll do that today.
Jessie Zhang: Maybe, Sanjeev, we can get feedback, then we can run again, ask people, then we can use these results and to see what data we can get.
Jessie Zhang: Then we can maybe change more.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, that makes sense. Maybe, like, once the feedback is there, let's just run the survey within the working group.
Sanjeev Suresh: And see if some… I mean, just analyze some results out of it. Yeah.
Sanjeev Suresh: And Jessie, in that version, I'll also give you edit access to the form itself, so you can, like, make minor tweaks, yeah.
Jessie Zhang: Okay, yeah, I might shift things and maybe changing some words, so it can be easy to… if each question, I have to take, like, a few minutes, it's gonna be a lot of time on that, so…
Jessie Zhang: Oh, by the way, I'm off. I'm off next two weeks, so I won't be here next two weeks, I'm gone.
Sanjeev Suresh: Next two weeks?
Jessie Zhang: Yeah.
Sanjeev Suresh: I mean, starting the 7th or such?
Jessie Zhang: Studying Action is Friday.
Jessie Zhang: Because Monday's a holiday, so I take it.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah.
Jessie Zhang: I'm also thinking, right, the service one, then we should start, Sanjeev, we were talking about, should start thinking about the outline of the white paper.
Jessie Zhang: I would like to maybe start after coming back.
Jessie Zhang: Jordan, is there any other thing we need to do?
Jessie Zhang: Are there higher priority things?
Jordan Augé: So… I guess, we need to progress on the taxonomy. I would like to…
Jordan Augé: leverage maybe the week after, once we are done with the survey, to ask people for feedback about D1.
Jordan Augé: And maybe we can focus more on, like,
Jordan Augé: 15 terms that we could want to contribute,
Jordan Augé: To the work stream, the priority ones.
Jordan Augé: I'd love to review those 15 and identify them, and maybe that could be a limited first review we could do.
Jordan Augé: Full deliverable, could be a second review, and that's something we'll continue in background.
Jordan Augé: Then we have the D2 gap analysis, so I don't know what we want to do. Maybe pause it a bit while we wait for the survey, or expect contributions, I don't know.
Jordan Augé: And finally, start seeing who is interested in contributing to further work.
Jordan Augé: Like was done in the previous meeting, like D3, D4?
Jordan Augé: So…
Jessie Zhang: I'll ask things after Nicolas. Nicolas just hand.
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah, so I have a… you know, just a heads up, it's really not a well-formed thought or question, because I'm not sure how that fits in our work or not. But let me just share a little bit of a… the work I'm doing right now is, analyzing
Nicolas Bonnet: user engagement with, our assistant at Autodesk. And there's something that's pretty fascinating, is that,
Nicolas Bonnet: There are users that, despite what I'm gonna say seems to be pretty negative, Tone of conversation.
Nicolas Bonnet: have high resilience, because it feels like they really are, trying to make it work. They know it can work, they're trying to make it work, and they'll… they'll…
Nicolas Bonnet: continue to work with it despite, its failings and its limitations. And then there are other users that seems, maybe, that are less…
Nicolas Bonnet: convinced.
Nicolas Bonnet: or that are… don't have the same kind of persistency, and they sort of give up. They don't even try. So, I'm saying all of this because it feels like there's something around
Nicolas Bonnet: That is not a one-size-fits-all from a…
Nicolas Bonnet: Reliability… so, not from systems, but from an end-user viewpoint, around how they react to inaccurate or unreliable kind of systems. So, I'm just a stream of consciousness here, I'm just sharing this because I feel like
Nicolas Bonnet: It's quite important to put the… The… the human…
Nicolas Bonnet: element, you know, in this, and that I feel like our assistants need to have some sort of
Nicolas Bonnet: capabilities to… To figure out how is this user
Nicolas Bonnet: how does this user want to interact with me? But I don't know if any of this fits into the work around accuracy and reliability. So just like, you know.
Nicolas Bonnet: saying all of this just here to share, because I feel there's a need to think about this, but I don't know if it fits within the scope of this specific working group. I'll stop here, just see how people react to that.
Jessie Zhang: Of course, I'm… we're from the… we're from the same working group at Autodesk, I do believe,
Jessie Zhang: when we say reliability and accuracy, right, how is… how are users reacting to that? That's reflecting the reliability and accuracy, so at least I think we should do the analysis, and at least in the white paper, we should include that part as well.
Jessie Zhang: That's mine.
Jessie Zhang: Mais faibaire.
Sanjeev Suresh: So include the… so if I'm understanding correctly, so include the part of how you, like, if you encounter accuracy, reliability issues, there are… some users might drop off, some users are resilient, that… that factor of it?
Nicolas Bonnet: Yes, yeah, so it's not… it's… it's almost like…
Nicolas Bonnet: We need to say, oh, yeah, that accuracy and reliability is inherent
Nicolas Bonnet: characteristics of the system, but this is not enough. Even if the system is… like, when the system is not reliable and not accurate.
Nicolas Bonnet: it… those… let's assume those are the property of the system. It is not always reliable, not always accurate, but still, some people will have resiliency and will continue to work it out, and some others
Nicolas Bonnet: with the same property of this system will have a completely different answer. So, I don't know where that fits, right? Because from a systems viewpoint, like, the user interaction with this needs to be handled.
Nicolas Bonnet: And I tend to think it's in the scope of accuracy and reliability, but it's the user interaction with the system, not the system itself, right?
Casper Nielsen: So, Nicolas, I think it's a really, really interesting point, right? Because especially this one, the system will respond to how the user interacts with it. The input will define a lot of the things the system will do afterwards.
Casper Nielsen: So I think it's a really interesting point, and I think there is something about it.
Casper Nielsen: Yeah, so…
Casper Nielsen: I don't know yet how to sort of encode it in, but I do think there's something about it. Like, I can… I can at least see on my kids, they are of the younger, younger generation. I can see, you know, my partner's kids, who is, you know, the Gen C generation. They have a very different perspective to AI than I do.
Casper Nielsen: Damn.
Casper Nielsen: and my peers, like, my colleagues are the same age as myself. So there is something about the demographics of users that interact with a different need, and that might very, very well have a very profound impact on how the system behaves underneath it, because it's an input-driven system.
Casper Nielsen: I think it's a very, very interesting point. I just… I have no clue yet how to sort of get it in.
Jordan Augé: Yeah, I said, I would tend to think that the user dimension is a really important one, because many systems will interface with user directly, if it's a chatbot, for example, or even indirectly.
Jordan Augé: And I guess there is a notion of utility of the answer you provide, whether it's fully accurate or not. It's to what extent it's useful to the users.
Jordan Augé: And we had a use case internally where we had, agents in CAICD trying to…
Jordan Augé: Review network changes. And there, maybe you could do, et rose?
Jordan Augé: Still, if you were, raising…
Jordan Augé: issues, it was still a win, because you could at least warn there is something you should not deploy to production. Then, of course, you have alert fatigue, because if you have too many false positives, that becomes useless, but you don't need full reliability to be completely accurate, so…
Jordan Augé: I guess this utility is a good way to map,
Nicolas Bonnet: I like that.
Jordan Augé: of the process to the usage by people. Like, in networking, they tend to do that, usually.
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah, I think it's an interesting viewpoint, like, for example, if the… Anything…
Jordan Augé: Actually, I think we should consider it in two or… deliverables.
Nicolas Bonnet: I would love to.
Jordan Augé: Missy.
Nicolas Bonnet: there's a… There's a…
Jordan Augé: Who, I think, needs to measure that some way.
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah, we need to figure out how to influence the behavior of the agent based on that sort of context of the user, and that's a thing that will impact reliability. And if we don't describe it in a formal way.
Nicolas Bonnet: people will just think, well, the system is reliable or it's not, and it's… the reliability is in the user interaction itself, which… with AI,
Nicolas Bonnet: you can put that back in the prompt. So there's a lot of things that you could do with AI to account for that user interaction that you couldn't do with a deterministic system. So I think that would be great to have that.
Jessie Zhang: I think we also have some definition when we did the terminology and taxonomy, so we already have some definition on the sentiment behavior analysis or something.
Jessie Zhang: And we can definitely add more details, especially on the… when we do the white paper.
Nicolas Bonnet: Well, thanks for hearing me out. It was not super well-formed as a question, but I feel there's something
Nicolas Bonnet: Important there.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah, I think, yeah, I agree with there's something important there on the user dimension of it. Something, again, stream of consciousness, something I was looking at recently, and so there's this, who verifies the agent?
Sanjeev Suresh: Europe's… there's a con… There's a workshop in Europe this year on who verifies the agent.
Sanjeev Suresh: For which I'm, going to review.
Sanjeev Suresh: papers on the program committee as well, so that… I mean, my motivation of getting involved in that was to also just get in this space more, and their goal is also, like, towards reliable agent development.
Sanjeev Suresh: And yeah, like a conference workshop on it.
Jessie Zhang: I have another question, right? So, totally agree with that, Nicolas, we need to add that. There's one more…
Jessie Zhang: One more dimension of it.
Jessie Zhang: Performance and cost.
Jessie Zhang: Yep. I don't know how other companies, how much you're spending, we are spending, a lot.
Jessie Zhang: on AI, and modeling.
Sanjeev Suresh: So, cost is really interesting, right? Because… but I don't know if it is neatly with… within, accuracy and reliability, or…
Jessie Zhang: Reliability, though.
Jessie Zhang: If you spend… if you have to pay so much, then you can't afford it. All the performance, latency, everything, the inference right now, our inference is kind of low, because we had to do different security concerns of it, so we have to route through certain, like, proxy, and then go in different places.
Jessie Zhang: Yeah, I know, I know it's controversial. I don't know any working group is looking at the performance and cost on this.
Jessie Zhang: If not, I felt like maybe.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: You might want to join Observability.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Okay. And tracing, because I am pushing very hard for us to say, well, yeah, we're measuring stuff, but why are we measuring it?
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: And one of the main things is evaluating the performance.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: And the other one would be cost.
Jessie Zhang: Yeah. I mean, cost will become a huge topic.
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah.
Sanjeev Suresh: And I think we should start, like, so in this survey question, so I think, like, what are the factors that affect your development? So cost is one, accuracy and reliability are other. I expect cost should be, like, one of the highest factors, maybe even above accuracy and reliability, that people are thinking about already, currently. And maybe for our future work, it is accuracy and reliability subject to cost constraints, subject to these.
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah, I think there's… we're starting to ask ourselves the question here, not all question requires Einstein to answer them, right? So, try to say, essentially, the computing… the compute cost needs to be related to the complexity of the question.
Nicolas Bonnet: And today, it's almost impossible to do, but that's where we should be headed, because some are good enough.
Nicolas Bonnet: with an open-weight model, and some of their other questions really require more thinking, so I think that's where we need to go. So it's opportunistic, based on the nature of the question.
Sanjeev Suresh: And I saw that, and maybe the answer to that, something we may recommend is also some kind of, like, I mean, standard towards routing, or some kind of smart router, and I saw someone also posted in our Discord regarding that a couple of days ago.
Sanjeev Suresh: Whether that's something we are thinking about discussing.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I'm gonna bring up the point that if we discuss these things,
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: We're gonna get people lying on the survey.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I don't expect people to say, I'm gonna break international law.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Because it's expensive. Because my manager said it has to be done by Thursday.
Sanjeev Suresh: I'm not sure I followed that.
Sanjeev Suresh: Can you edit?
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Okay, so, basically, if we're… we're discussing cost, Saying that we're very cost-conscious.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Can be framed as, we are cheap.
Sanjeev Suresh: Hmm.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Saying that we're cheap?
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Is saying that we are not delivering quality to our users.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I think that some people may be encouraged to lie on the survey.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: And to exaggerate their love of the users versus their love of money.
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah. Matthew, maybe one way to answer… to discriminate between the two is to ask the question, does your company has any cost control?
Nicolas Bonnet: To, you know, like, ask the question in a way, like, you say, rather than say, are you serious about it, which people are gonna say, oh, the user comes first, at whatever cost, if you say, if there… what kind of controls do you have, that might elicit…
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Absolutely. I just want to make sure that we don't say, Do you…
Nicolas Bonnet: Sacrifice security.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Accuracy in case… in favor of cost.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Do you throw your users under the bus?
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, fair, yeah.
Jessie Zhang: Is there any other working group also looking harness?
Jessie Zhang: some kind of… Standard way. I need to look at.
Sanjeev Suresh: Massage.
Jessie Zhang: on my side.
Sanjeev Suresh: So, I don't know about Harlanas, I mean, but under the Agentic Foundation, Goose is the open source harness, that's part of the foundation, so, I mean, people…
Sanjeev Suresh: Working on ghosts, might be thinking about harnesses, and…
Sanjeev Suresh: In general. If you're on some point, yeah.
Jessie Zhang: Because what I'm looking at is, I found out at least a, from… because of this cost, because of,
Jessie Zhang: You're using someone else's model, right? You are not using your own personal, like, company trend. So I started looking at putting more harness in it, also doing caching. I can't believe I'm going back to a very basic thing. I'm doing caching, I'm doing all different things in there.
Jessie Zhang: because trying to make it, like, a lower latency, or lower the cost, so it doesn't need to always go to LLM, so I always have that, some quick.
Jessie Zhang: search, and the semantic search, and I store all the understanding, and the nostril is going to use LLM, so…
Sanjeev Suresh: like, I know Ghost, as supports, like, things like local inference, you can have your own local models.
Sanjeev Suresh: yeah.
Jessie Zhang: It'd be good to know how many companies are using the no command. We're not, so… Yeah. Not yet. Security, right? It's all about security concern, internal.
Jessie Zhang: Or a student.
Jordan Augé: Okay, so… Yep.
Sanjeev Suresh: No, no, I'll drop off shortly, just, I mean, if there's any more, like, feedback, please, on the survey, please leave on Discord.
Sanjeev Suresh: And, and Jessie, maybe, like, like, I don't know if you, if you want to meet sometime before you head out, just…
Sanjeev Suresh: To sing together.
Jessie Zhang: Yep, we can sync maybe, Thursday morning.
Sanjeev Suresh: Sounds.
Jordan Augé: So, do you want me to ask people… so I will ask to review the survey before the end of the week. Do you want me to ask them also to have a run at it, or is it too early? Like, early next week, or something?
Sanjeev Suresh: How are you doing?
Jordan Augé: Well, I mean…
Sanjeev Suresh: I mean, the best way to review it might be actually just to, I mean, run… I mean, like, even if not the full final answers, just to actually go through it, because when you see the survey, you'll feel like, hey, this is not ordered correctly, or this wording feels off to me.
Sanjeev Suresh: As opposed to the PR, and then leave feedback on the PR.
Sanjeev Suresh: Yeah.
Jessie Zhang: Also, Jordan, you're talking about, we guarantee
Jessie Zhang: being, like, anonymous, right? I… I was actually originally talking to Sanjeev. I was thinking about using user information to figure out their organization, their types of business. If we need to, we can just hide all of those.
Jessie Zhang: Or we should just… if we say, hey, we really want a true honest answer, let's just say we're gonna guarantee that, then we're gonna mask all the data, all the user data, we can do that.
Jordan Augé: It was just to answer Matthew's question about people will cheat. If they feel like they will be exposed, that's…
Jessie Zhang: Yeah, yeah. Yeah, I think, Sanjeev, you already have something saying we're gonna do, right? So let's, let's just say, yeah, we guarantee.
Sanjeev Suresh: Alright, thank you, folks.
Jordan Augé: Thanks a lot.
Jessie Zhang: Later.
Jordan Augé: So… For the last part, I think it can be very fast, so…
Jordan Augé: it was just about progress on day one, so I know there have been a few reviews on the pull request, I did not have a look yet, but
Jordan Augé: I guess I will ask people to continue commenting on it from
Jordan Augé: When we're done with the survey.
Jordan Augé: about the main definitions, I was wondering if we want, maybe, to…
Jordan Augé: start with the central part, which is the definition of accuracy, reliability, and the different sub-dimensions. And I guess that's where we might, really define,
Jordan Augé: Everything which is about performance, cost, reliability…
Jordan Augé: The different interfaces, like, with users, with the infrastructure, etc, so…
Jordan Augé: Trying to take scope our first contribution around the… what defines…
Jordan Augé: the system, the dimensions, etc. So maybe it's a good way to…
Jordan Augé: They limit a shorter set of terms.
Jordan Augé: This will be one chapter in the deliverable, so we could focus on it and maybe extend.
Jordan Augé: Yep, and that's…
Jessie Zhang: Where do you, where do you want us to put the feedback? It's on the…
Jessie Zhang: GitHub, or is it… There aren't, you know, their documents.
Jordan Augé: So, I think now we have a PR on GitHub, which is more up-to-date, that should be the direct version.
Jordan Augé: One thing we discussed with Casper that we could do is, like, having one or two-week sessions
Jordan Augé: where we accept reviews, and we comment on the PR, and every week or second week, when we have enough content, we merge the version, we try to clean comments, make the version, and start another round of reviews.
Jordan Augé: And we could, use the meetings also to make a quick update about where we are.
Jordan Augé: So, first feedback, I think, would be to comment on the table of contents. Do you think…
Jordan Augé: it's enough, etc, and then we can focus on the terms. That's what I will propose in the meetings.
Jordan Augé: But given the low feedback that we have, I really want that we focus on the survey first, which is the most urgent part, and I will ask people about D1 only when we are done, maybe.
Jordan Augé: And that's all I had about terminology.
Jordan Augé: I don't know, so, Matthew, you're maybe offline, but if you have any ask from the work stream about how it's progressing, but you can
Jordan Augé: Tell us offline, also?
Jordan Augé: And, last part is, and maybe, Casper, I need your help. So, in the last meeting, you started talking about,
Jordan Augé: work we might want to do outside of D1, D2?
Jordan Augé: So, I don't know if you had a… Updates…
Jordan Augé: If there are a person in the meeting connected that have a topic they would like to work, which is not covered by D1D2,
Jordan Augé: They would like to start.
Jordan Augé: So… Don't hesitate to exchange, because we could help set priorities and… See what to tackle.
Jordan Augé: Do you see anything else to discuss?
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I'm gonna propose a little something.
Jordan Augé: Yep.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I propose this for every meeting I'm in, where it's like any other business. Is there any news in the world of AI that we should be aware of from an ac…
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Accuracy and Reliability point of view.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I'm wondering, like, OpenAI pulling away from cursor.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Will this have an impact on… AI Reliability and Accuracy.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: And random model changes because the empires don't like each other.
Nicolas Bonnet: Those are our big questions.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Absolutely.
Nicolas Bonnet: I…
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I'm not asking for answers, it's just a way to, like, keep us up to date on all the news, because there is way too much news happening right now.
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah, I think what it echoes with me is the incredibly complex task of benchmarking our solutions.
Nicolas Bonnet: With the… the fact that underneath
Nicolas Bonnet: The system that we use underneath change
Nicolas Bonnet: are so, change all the time. Like, you know, so if you use one version versus another version, if you say, hey, we have a system that is now stable, we should consider how is this going to impact the quality of our outputs if we change the version of the model.
Nicolas Bonnet: Then, it's in a huge amount of work to reassess, and so that constant need to benchmark a moving target is… is,
Nicolas Bonnet: Is,
Nicolas Bonnet: overwhelming, to say the least. So, I think that will impact progress, because this changes all the time.
Nicolas Bonnet: in a way that is… that it seems closer to chaos than… than structure progress. It's like, it improves on one… on one side, and then it regresses on the other side.
Nicolas Bonnet: So it's extremely difficult to, to plan. So, I don't know if this directly answers what you say, Matthew, but I feel like
Nicolas Bonnet: I think keeping up with all those different choices of foundation model vendors that we could use and their version is,
Nicolas Bonnet: It's creating so much churn.
Nicolas Bonnet: And will create an enormous amount of impact with end users if we don't.
Nicolas Bonnet: That they… you know, there's a big risk there.
Jordan Augé: And actually, we have the same with RNCs, because,
Jordan Augé: We never really talked about it, I guess, but a lot of people, they are using Cloud Code as a harness also to run agents, but there… I don't think you have a lot of control about the version of the harness, even so.
Jordan Augé: You get updates, but you don't know what's happened under the scene, so… I wonder how…
Jordan Augé: Telemetry observability wants to tackle this, by the way.
Jordan Augé: Because I'm not sure there will be a lot of… Matrix available?
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: We're still at the foundation level there.
Jordan Augé: Okay.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Like, the primitivist level.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I… I wrote a… Big.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Rundown of the AI landscape, by the way.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I'm not going to present it here, because I thought it would take 10 minutes, and with questions, it took an hour and a half.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: But I am going to share the slides.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: In fact, I'll do one better. I'll share my entire slide… my entire public slide deck.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: It's the one for AIF, the third one in there.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: All these slides are CCSA,
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: So, feel free to take as much as you want.
Jordan Augé: Thank you.
Jordan Augé: Anything else someone willing to share?
Jessie Zhang: I am very interested in those…
Jessie Zhang: those new, like, open source models, you can… you can distill, because that is really gonna change landscape, right? Some of them, probably, you can distill for your laptop. Some of them you can do, like, your host, a company hosted, right? So you don't have to, be tied to
Jessie Zhang: Like, I saw a vehicle, different, different companies,
Jessie Zhang: I don't know whether other companies are doing that, and what you find.
Jessie Zhang: And I know we're… some of the people in my company, in our company were doing that. We're also doing it at home.
Jessie Zhang: or have our home service distilled, right? Just don't want to pay. Let me say that. Number one, don't want to pay. Number two is also, so you train with your needs, and it's easy, better control.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: It's good enough.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I have a couple articles on…
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: This, like, if you look at LinkedIn, you'll see them, but,
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: I'm just going to mention, and I can't say Ericsson's stance on this, public or publicly speaking, however.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: You might want to look into data centers that just opened in Sweden, purchasing abnormally large amounts of GPUs.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: And… I'm sure you can figure out what GPUs are being used for, it's not for video games.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: It… Means that people
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: are looking into open models. Even if they don't perform as well, they give you data sovereignty.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: That's a big plus.
Nicolas Bonnet: Yeah.
Jessie Zhang: What do you even think about chemic history? Seems to be, really good, but it's much larger.
Jessie Zhang: So those are things I felt like maybe come to this. So we're talking about reliability, but I felt like everything's related to reliability.
Jessie Zhang: Because right now, there are a lot of models you really cannot control, then you have to put a lot of contacts in.
Jessie Zhang: And in order to get better results. And if you have your own model.
Jessie Zhang: And this is an easier control. This is what I think.
Jordan Augé: Any other reaction or something to share?
Jordan Augé: So, I encourage you to continue the discussion on Discord, so if we can try to keep the channel active, that could…
Jordan Augé: Maybe help involve more people, so…
Jordan Augé: And, so I'll try to post minutes with the action points, mostly on the survey.
Jordan Augé: And, feel free to exchange about that.
Jordan Augé: And,
Jordan Augé: See you next time. So, I'll ping also to see if we want to have an intermediate meeting next week.
Jordan Augé: To sync on the survey, and then,
Jordan Augé: Otherwise, see you in the next meeting.
Jordan Augé: Thanks, everyone.
Jessie Zhang: Yes.
Casper Nielsen: Bye-bye.
Reliably Matthew Khouzam: Bio!